BSc GRASIELE ROMANZINI-BEZERRA

MASTER STUDENT

Brazilian Center for Research in Physics, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

■ bezerragrasiele@gmail.com

bezerragrasi.github.io

in grasiele-romanzini-bezerra

Bezerragrasi

PROFILE _____

Grasiele Romanzini Bezerra currently lives in Leeds, England and have legal right to live and work in UK. She holds master degree in physics (2023) at Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Brazil, and a bachelor degree in Physics (2020) from Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul (UFRGS), Brazil. Besides having an advanced knowledge in data science and excellent computational skills, she also has 5 years experience in analyse scientific and social data using a varied range of programming languages, such as python, R and C.

EDUCATION _____

Master in Cosmology: Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil (2023).

BSc in Physics: Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Brazil (2020).

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE _____

Master Student

Brazilian Center for Research in Physics, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

• **Project:** Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Einstein Rings and Velocity Dispersion

Aug 2021 - Jul 2023

- Supervisor: Dr. Martin Makler
- Co-Supervisor: Dr. Cristina Furlanetto
- Apply Bayesian analyses and hypothesis test tp lensing galaxies data.

Scientific Initiation

Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

Project: Testing the Parameterized Post-Newtonian Gravity with Strong Gravitational Lensing

Jan 2019 - Feb 2020

- Advisor: Dr. Cristina Furlanetto
- Apply likelihood inference to data of 103 lensing galaxies from 4 different surveys.

Internship

Physics Institute, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil

• Project: Gender Diversity in Science

Jun 2015 - Jul 2019

- Advisor: Dr. Marcia C. B. Barbosa
- Mining and analyse the data of 5 thousand Brazilian scientist to gain insights on gender bias.

PUBLICATIONS __

Bezerra, Grasiele Romanzini, Daniela Lazzaro, Aruquia Peixoto, Maria Margaret Lopes, C Andrade, H. J. N. Lopes, and Márcia C. Barbosa (2019). "Female Researchers in Science in Brazil: the Scissors Effect". In: *La Brecha de Género en Matemática, Computación y Ciencias Naturales*. Edited by Lilia Meza Montes and Silvina Ponce Dawson. Mexican Physic Society, pages 55–67.

Ferrari, Nathália C, Raquel Martell, Daniela H Okido, **Grasiele Romanzini**, Viviane Magnan, Márcia C Barbosa, and Carolina Brito (2018). "Geographic and gender diversity in the Brazilian Academy of Sciences". In: *Anais da Academia Brasileira de Ciências* 90.2, pages 2543–2552.

Bezerra, **Grasiele** and Marcia C Barbosa (2016). "Mulheres na física no brasil". In: *SBF Sociedade Brasileira de Física – 50 anos – 1966 – 2016 (Book of 50 years of the Brazilian physic society)*. Edited by Alicia Ivanissevich and Cássio Leite Vieira. Brazilian Physic Society, pages 132–135.

EVENTS ___

Poster Presentation - Impact of Galaxy Dynamics on Modified Gravity Constraints from Strong Lensing Systems: IAUS 381: Strong gravitational lensing in the era of Big Data, Jun 2023.

Oral Presentation - Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Velocity Dispersion in Einstein Rings Systems: As Astrocientistas II: Brazilian Meeting of Girls and Women in Astrophysics, Gravitation, and Cosmology, Feb 2023.

Oral Presentation - Testing Gravity with Einstein Rings and Velocity Dispersion: II Workshop on Lensing by Galaxies and Clusters, Aug 2022.

Flash Talk - Galaxy Dynamics and Modified Gravity from Velocity Dispersion in E-Rings Systems: Cosmology from Home 2022, Jul 2022.

Oral Presentation - Testing the Parameterized Post-Newtonian Gravity with Strong Gravitational Lensing: First Workshop on Lensing by Galaxies and Clusters, Federal University of Rio Grande do Sul, Porto Alegre, RS, Brazil. Oct 2019.

Poster Presentation - Geographic and Gender Diversity in the Brazilian Academy of Sciences: IX Workshop in Complexity of Water and Other Liquids, Federal University of Pelotas, UFPel, Pelotas, RS, Brazil. Nov 2018.

SCHOOLS

Summer School: Astroinformatics II, Center for Astrostatistics, The Pennsylvania State University, USA. Jun 2022

Summer School: Statistics for Astronomers XVII, Center for Astrostatistics, The Pennsylvania State University, USA. Jun 2022

Winter school: XIII CBPF's winter school, Brazilian Center for Research in Physics (CBPF), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. December Aug 2021.

Winter School: Astrophysical Winter 2019, Center for Astrophysics and Cosmology of the UFES, Castelo, ES, Brazil. Aug 2019.

PROFESSIONAL TRAINING _____

Jul 2021 - Professional Certificate in Data Science, Harvard.

Jun 2021 - MOOC - Data Visualization and Communication with Tableau, Duke University.

Mar 2021 - MOOC - Privacy Law and Data Protection, University of Pennsylvania.

Jan 2021 - MOOC - Data Analytic en Power Bl, Coursera Project Network.

Aug 2020 - MOOC - Data-driven Astronomy, The University of Sydney.

grasiere R. Bezerra